#### **Andrew Reece**

5 Wordsworth Road, Loughborough, Leicestershire, LE11 4LG
<a href="mailto:azmreece@gmail.com">azmreece@gmail.com</a> andrewreece.co.uk uk.linkedin.com/in/azmreece
07553 137962
06 March 1994

#### **Profile**

Ergonomics graduate, school and university scholar and CIEHF student representative with programming experience. Technical, artistic, design and psychology interests and qualifications. Demonstrable range of experience of leadership, collaboration and communication through jobs, courses, expeditions and voluntary work. Keen to further my career involving the application of human factors.

## Skills, knowledge and experience

#### Scientific and research

- Ergonomics: physical, psychological, legal, environmental, complex systems, barrier management
- Final year project on improving the graphical representation of hierarchical task analysis
- Maths: statistics at university; vectors, matrices, calculus and probability for IB; self-study
- Physics: mechanics, thermal physics, waves, atomic and nuclear physics, electricity, circuits/electronics, astrophysics, fluid dynamics and medical physics
- Psychology: university and school study of biological, cognitive, and sociocultural levels of analysis
- Planning, analysing and carrying out self-led scientific research
- Qualitative and quantitative methodology: environmental ergonomics survey

## **Technology**

- Intermediate use of programming languages: C, Go, Javascript, Rust, Python, Bash, PHP, x86 asm
- Programming experience: automating admin tasks, web back-end, psychology experiment and data collection, games (involving graphics, sound and user input), desktop software, text editor (VIM) scripting. Some smaller projects are hosted at <a href="mailto:github.com/azmr">github.com/azmr</a>
- HCI: experience evaluating and improving website design based on heuristics and user trials
- UX: creating and using personas; building up from wireframes to interactive prototypes with Axure
- CAD/CAM: work at Custom Design Technologies and Eurocopter; LSU CAD society
- Use of vector (Inkscape) and raster programs (Photoshop, GIMP)

#### **Design and creative**

- Creative problem solving (e.g. TRIZ) with brand-appropriate presentation: Leatherman redesign
- Prototyping for personal and university projects: ergonomics testing for a kettle redesign
- Photography and videography: sports (mostly gymnastics), products and people (model headshots)
- Student gymnastics club committee member: media representative (videos, photos, promotions)
- Leatherwork: bags, cases, wallets, sheaths; attended shoe-making conference
- Fabric/sewing/knitting: collared shirt, bag, corset, scarf and hats created to size
- Blacksmithing: individually and on course using traditional Saxon methods to make kitchen knife
- Web and graphic design: for personal/client sites and freeBadge; logos, banners, posters
- Drawing skills: life, <u>animation</u>, visual arts at higher level in IB
- Resistant materials GCSEs: designing and making a multimedia stand

#### Leadership and teamwork

- CIEHF student representative; secretariat at 2017 CIEHF annual conference
- Giving presentations in teams and individually e.g. on legal requirements for manufacturers
- Residential activities leader with international children aged 10-15
- Head of graphics in college charity group Invisible Children
- Duke of Edinburgh Gold expeditions
- Led the winning team at Smallpeice Trust materials engineering course
- Sole sales assistant at Kirtlington village shop; volunteer at Tackley Village Shop
- Tutoring students at GCSE level and below

# **Education**

Dates	School/college	Course	Grade
Oct 2014 – July 2017	Loughborough University (3x Scholarship for Academic Excellence)	Ergonomics (Human Factors Design) BSc	1st (Hons)
Sept 2010 – May 2013	St. Clare's, Oxford (major scholarship; multiple principal's high achievement awards)	International baccalaureate diploma programme	42/45
Sept 2007 – June 2010	Abingdon School, Oxon (major scholarship)	AS French 10 IGCSE/GCSEs	B 10 A* and A

# **Employment and work experience**

Dates	Employer	Job title/duties
June 2017 – August 2017	Loughborough University	Data analyst, research assistant
May 2017 – June 2017	Deliveroo	Food delivery by bike
April 2017	CIEHF	Conference secretariat
July 2015 – date	Self-employed	Web developer, labourer, waiter/barman
July 2014	MainTool	Product designer/prototyper
Jan 2014 – date	Ember Creations facebook.com/embercreations	Founder, craftsman, full stack web developer, product photographer
Jan 2014 – June 2014	Kirtlington shop	Assistant, frequently in sole charge
Sept 2013 – Jan 2014	Custom Design Technologies, Brackley	Electronic & physical assembly, QA, fire safety, packaging/handling goods, web design, photography, machinery operation, marketing, customer interaction
July 2013	Simcross Welding Services	Welding, oxy-acetylene cutting, spraypainting, machinery use
July 2012 – July 2013	St. Clare's, Oxford	Activities staff with international 10-15yr olds
April 2012 – date	Self-employed	Part-time maths, physics and English tutor
July 2011	London Borough of Hillingdon Housing Service	Observed all aspects of council housing – repairs; care; adaptations; front end
July 2011 – August 2011	St. Clare's Oxford	Part-time student ambassador
July 2010	Eurocopter, Kidlington	CAD and workshop assistant
2008 - 2012	Tackley Village Shop	Volunteer - serving, stocking up, cleaning

## **Interests**

#### Active:

Gymnastics (BG member, AU Colours, medalled in BUCS), freerunning/parkour, climbing (UK & France), capoeira, mixed martial arts, freediving, snowboarding, flatland BMX, Duke of Edinburgh Gold **Creative**:

Programming, leatherwork, woodwork, metalwork (blacksmithing, aluminium casting), design, electronics, piano, sewing, cooking, photography (published in national newspaper), researching unfamiliar topics

## Referees

On request